A Guide to the Alfred Ezra Mirsky papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA131
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Correspondence, 1929 1942-1974; 2
  - Na, 53 letters (Box 10)
    - National Academy of Sciences, 53 letters
      Includes 1956 report of NAS Committee on Loyalty in govt supported research; 2 items 1963 March 11 and 25 on April meeting; 1971 President Handler testimony before the Subcommittee on Science, Research and Development of the Committee on Science and Astronautics; 1972 NAS statement concerning bombing in Vietnam.
      - Foreign Associates and Refugees, 25 letters (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - Proceedings, 123 letters (Box 10, Folder 3)
        Includes mss reviews.
      - National Science Foundation, 1956-1971; 27 letters (Box 10, Folder 5)
        Correspondence. Includes some travel grants.
      - Grant Proposal Evaluations, 1953-1974 (Box 10)
        - A-C
          - Alfert, M.
          - Bresnick, Edward
          - Brunkhorst, Willa K., 2 letters
          - Buchanan, J.M.
          - Busch, Harris, 2 letters
          - Cox, Rody R.
        - D-G
          - de la Torre, L.
            (see Torre)
          - Ferguson, J.J.
          - Gehrke, C.W.
          - Goldbern, E.
          - Goodwin, George H.
        - H-O
          - Holbrook, David J. Jr.
          - Hunter, F.R.
          - Jost, Jean-Pierre
          - Kelsall, Margaret A.
          - Kit, Saul
          - Lepkovsky, Samuel
          - Merriam, Robert W.
          - Miller, S.L.
          - Moore, Peter R.
          - Olson, Mark O.
        - P-W
          - Petermann, Mary L.
          - Pollister, Arthur W.
          - Roth, Jay S.
          - Scharff, Matthew D.
          - Terry, Kelland D.
          - Thornborough John R.
          - Tomizawa, H.H.
          - Torre de la, L.
          - Wang, Tung-yue
          - Weymouth, P.P.
          - Wu, Szu-Hsiae
  - N-Neu (Box 11)
    - Nadler, Kenneth D., 1 letter
    - Nam, Kim Keh, 1 letter
    - Naora, Hiroto. RI research associate, 1958 December-1960 July; 56 letters
    - Nardone, Roland M., 2 letters
    - Nathanson, Robert, 2 letters
    - The Nation, 11 letters
    - National Book Committee, 2 letters
    - National Institute of Health, 6 letters
      Includes Paul Kirk, Silvio Fiala, Nathanial Kurnick grant application reviews.
    - National Research Council, 1950-1965; 11 letters
      Served on Panel on Cytochemistry, Committee on Growth. Includes duplicated material.
    - Natori, Yasuo, 2 letters
    - Nature. Items on 1964 Sept 25-Oct 14 Palermo summer course, 1964 September 25-October 14; 18 letters
    - Nayar, K.K., 3 letters
    - Neel, James V. Jane Schultz recommendation, 1 letter
    - Neghme, Amador, 7 letters
    - Nelson, Bill, 2 letters
    - Neogy, R.K., 2 letters
    - Neurath, Hans. Silvio Fiala recommendation; Dounce & Umana ms review, 6 letters
  - New-Ny (Box 11)
    - New Delhi, 2 letters
    - New England Institute, 3 letters
    - New York Academy of Sciences, 9 letters
      Includes James Quattrochi ms review.
    - New York Heart Association, 1963-1972; 23 letters
      Items on 1964 Feb 7-8 N Y Heart Symposium. Includes typescript of address.
    - New York Times. Concerning Arthur Schlesinger Jr. City University appointment, 3 letters
    - New York University. 1970 Jan 14 biology group address, 1970 January 14; 2 letters
    - Nikolov, T.K., 8 letters
    - Niu, Man'-Chiang, 1953-1964; 51 letters
    - Nolte, R.H., 1 letter
    - Nord, F.F., 4 letters
    - Norling, Greg, 2 letters
    - Northrop, John H. 1 holograph, 6 letters
    - Nottebohm, Fernando, 1 letter
    - Novikoff, Alex B., 1951-1963; 15 letters
    - Noyes, W. Albert, 1 letter
    - Nyham, William L., 2 letters
  - O-Ov (Box 11)
    - Oak Ridge National Laboratory. Alexander Hollaender correspondence, 5 letters
    - O'Brien, ?.Holograph, 1 letter
    - Ochoa, Severo, 2 letters
    - Odessey, Richard. Admission application with college transcript, 3 letters
    - O'Donnell, Elsa H., 1 letter
    - Ogur, Maurice, 2 letters
    - Ohba, Yoshiki, 2 letters
    - Ohsaka, Akira, 4 letters
    - O'Kelley, J.C., 3 letters
    - Olby, Robert, 5 letters
    - Olins, Donald E. Clarence Connelly recommendation, 3 letters
    - Oliver, Wade, 2 letters
    - One 2R Instruments for Research and Industry, 1 letter
    - Oparin, A.I., 6 letters
    - Orahovac, D.D., 1 letter
    - Orbis Publishing Co., 2 letters
    - Ord, Margery, 15 letters
      Includes items on Rachel Gillet student admission.
    - Orr, Richard H., 2 letters
    - Ortuzar, Jorge, 1 letter
    - Osborne, H. Princeton Conference on Science Information, 1961 March 5-7; 8 letters
      Includes A.E. Mirsky evaluation letter.
    - Osgood, Edwin E., 5 letters
    - Osmundsen, John A., 1 letter
    - Osmundsen, Sheila, 1 letter
    - Osterhout, Ikki, 1 letter
    - Osterhout, W.J.V. 1 holograph, 4 letters
    - Ottowa, 2 letters
    - Overend, W.G., 11 letters
  - Os (Box 11)
    - Osawa, Syozo, 1953-1973; 72 letters
  - Pa (Box 11)
    - Panda, Nimai Chara, 1964-1974; 87 letters
      Includes acctg records.
  - P-Piel (Box 12)
    - Packchanian, A. Job inquiry for G. Barsekyn, 2 letters
    - Page, Irwin H., 1 letter
    - Painter, Theophilus.; 1 holograph, 1944-1964; 5 letters
    - Palade, George, 2 letters
    - Paley, Sanford L., 3 letters
    - Panusz, Henryk, 20 letters
      Includes recommendation for.
    - Pappenheim, John, 4 letters
    - Paradowski, Robert J. Arrangements for interview about Linus Pauling, 2 letters
    - Pardee, Arthur B., 1 letter
    - Parthasarathy, M.D., 1 letter
    - Paul, John, 2 letters
    - Pauling, Linus, 2 letters
    - Pavan, Crodowaldo, 1955-1966; 7 letters
    - Payes, Benjamin, 2 letters
    - Pearce, Nancy, 1 letter
    - Pearincott, Joseph V., 2 letters
    - Pearson, Oliver P., 6 letters
    - Peattie, Donald O., 3 letters
    - Pedersen, O. Margery, 2 letters
    - Pedersen, Thoru, 8 letters
    - Pelc, S.R., 14 letters
      Includes job inquiry for M. Owen; comments on Nature note.
    - Penndorf, Paul. Congratulations letter, 1 letter
    - Penrose, L.S., 6 letters
    - Pepper, Claude. Concerning drug research support, 3 letters
    - Perkins-Elmer Corp., 2 letters
    - Perlman, Stanley. Admission application with college transcript, 6 letters
    - Person, Philip, 2 letters
    - Petrezelka, Charles, 2 letters
    - Pfeiffer, E., 2 letters
    - Phegan, W.D., 2 letters
    - Phillips, G.R., 1 letter
    - Philpot, J. St. L., 3 letters
    - Piel, Gerard, 6 letters
    - Piel, Jonathan, 1 letter
  - Pier-Pu (Box 12)
    - Pierce, Barry, 1 letter
    - Pilownic, Teodor, 1 letter
    - Pinsky, Edith, 2 letters
    - Piping Systems, 1 letter
    - Pittenger, T.H., 2 letters
    - Pizzolongo, Paolo, 2 letters
    - Plant and Cell Physiology, 2 letters
    - Platt, Rutherford, 5 letters
      Includes K. Bahadur comments on Reader's Digest article.
    - Plattsburgh State University, 2 letters
    - Plough, Harold H. On 1963 April 17 Amherst seminar, 1 letter
    - Pluznik, Dov, 2 letters
    - Pogo, O. Oscar and Beatriz, 1960-1974; 51 letters
      Includes A.O. Pogo recommendation for membership in Am Soc Biol Chem and other recommendations; mss reviews.
    - Polanyi, George. On having Darlington on committee concerned with freedom in the modern world, 1 letter
    - Pollard, Morris, 5 letters
    - Polli, E.E., 2 letters
    - Ponnamperuma, Cyril. Wakulla Springs, Fla conference, 1963 October 27-30; 8 letters
    - Porter, Bruce, 2 letters
    - Portney, Robert, 1 letter
    - Portugal, Franklin H., 5 letters
    - Poussaint, Alvin F., 3 letters
    - Price, Charles C., 2 letters
    - Prosser, C. Ladd. Ford Foundation travel grant recommendations for Prasad, Thapliyal and Seshachar, 2 letters
    - Puccia, Egidio, 1 letter
    - Puck, Theodore T. Items on Puck RI seminar arrangement, 15 letters
    - Purcell, Elizabeth, 1 letter
    - Purdue University, 2 letters
    - Purko, J., 2 letters
    - Pusey, Nathan. first convocation presentation address for honorary degree, 1959 May 2; 1 letter
    - Putnam's Sons, G.P., 2 letters
  - Q-Re (Box 12)
    - Quastel, J.H., 2 letters
    - Rafferty, Keen A., 2 letters
    - Ragg, D., 2 letters
    - Rajalakshmi, M.A., 3 letters
    - Ramasarma, T. Comments on Nature note, 2 letters
    - Ramirez, Oscar, 2 letters
    - Randall,?. London project evaluation to G.R. Pomerat, RF, 1 letter
    - Ranji, Silvio. Item concerning C. Paoletti, 6 letters
    - Rao, K.S. Bhushana, 3 letters
    - Rao, M.V. Narasimha, 2 letters
    - Rau, U. Vasudeva, 1 letter
    - Rauch, Nancy. Fordham University address, 1972 May 3; 5 letters
    - Reid, Eric, 4 letters
    - Reimann, Stanley P. Fox Chase, Phila conference for Tobacco Industry Research Committee, 1962 April 21; 3 letters
    - Reinhold Book Division.; Correspondence primarily with H.R. Simonds, 1960-1964; 27 letters
    - Reio, V., 2 letters
    - Reverberi, Guiseppe, 1951-1974; 49 letters
      Includes items on 1967 Sept 25-Oct 14 Palermo, Italy 2nd Int'l Summer Course chairman.
  - Rh-Ru (Box 12)
    - Rhoades, Marcus, 9 letters
    - Rhoades, Marcus Jr., 1 letter
    - Richter, Curt, 1 letter
    - Rifkind, Daniel, 1 letter
    - Rifkind, Mary R., 1 letter
    - Rigler, Rudolph, 2 letters
    - Riker, Walter F., 2 letters
    - Riley, James F., 1 letter
    - Rinaldini, Luis M., 4 letters
    - Ris, Hans. Holograph. Concerning Ris RF fellowship, 1 letter
    - Rivers, Thomas M., 1957 January 7-9; 31 letters
      Includes items on 1957 Jan 7-9 New York Academy of Sciences address.
    - Robapharm Inc., 5 letters
    - Robbins, William J., 7 letters
    - Robinson, Howard A. Concerning Christmas Lectures, 3 letters
    - Robinson, Kathleen, 2 letters
    - Rochester University of. address, 1964 March 13; 4 letters
    - Rockefeller, David Mrs, 2 letters
    - Roepke, M.H., 2 letters
    - Rogers, Stanfield, 9 letters
    - Roman, Herschel L., 2 letters
    - Roos, Thomas B., 3 letters
    - Roose, Kenneth D., 2 letters
    - Rosen, Moshe, 2 letters
    - Rosen, Roberta, 2 letters
    - Rosenzweig, Mark R., 1 letter
    - Rossi, Bruno, 2 letters
    - Rotell, Thomas M., 2 letters
    - Rothschild, Hanna, 1 letter
    - Rothschild, Lord, 5 letters
      Includes items on Chayen; Danielli evaluations.
    - Rothstein, Howard, 3 letters
    - Rous, Peyton. 2 holographs, 3 letters
    - Royal Society. Society's Tercentary celebration, 1960 July; 3 letters
    - Royal Society of Medicine, 2 letters
    - Rudkin, George, 1 letter
    - Runnström, John. Stockholm conference, 1952 September 2-6; 3 letters
    - Rutman, Robert, 5 letters
    - Ryan, Francis J. On RI support X International Congress of Genetics, Montreal, Canada Ryan, Regina (2), 5 letters
      Includes comments on Barry Commoner "The Closing Circle".
    - Ruzicska, Peter, 1 letter
  - Ro (Box 12)
    Rockefeller Foundation.; Primarily dealing with funding various projects and trips.
    - Rockefeller Foundation, 1951-1963; 53 letters
      Primarily dealing with funding various projects and trips.
  - S-Schn (Box 12)
    - Sachs, Leo. Job inquiry for Dov Pluznik, 3 letters
    - Saetren, Hans.; Primarily letters of recommendation, 1948-1957; 15 letters
    - Sagan, Carl, 2 letters
    - Sagan, Lynn, 2 letters
    - Sagar, V.K., 2 letters
    - Saha, Anil, 3 letters
    - Saifer, A., 2 letters
    - Salisbury, Frank, 1 letter
    - Saltmarsh, John, 1 letter
    - Sanday, Peggy, 1 letter
    - Sandow, Alexander, 3 letters
    - Sandritter, W. Job inquiry for Mr. Böhm, 2 letters
    - Sangiorgio, Frank. Admission application, 2 letters
    - Sapozhnikow, D.J., 2 letters
    - Sarkar, A., 2 letters
    - Sarkar, N.K., 2 letters
    - Sarkar, S., 1 letter
    - Sarojini, S., 2 letters
    - Saskatchewan University. Saskatoon, Canada, Genetics Soc of Canada, Annual Invitational lecture, 1964 May 7-8; 10 letters
    - Scarano, Eduardo, 6 letters
    - Scharrer, Ernst, 2 letters
    - Scheer, B.T., 1 letter
    - Scheraga, H.A., 1 letter
    - Schering Corp. In vitro lab work gift, 5 letters
    - Schiff, H.I., 1 letter
    - Schindler, Arthur. Recommendation for, 1 letter
    - Schmidt, Carl F. D. Jenden and N. Giarman nomination recommendations to NAS, 2 letters
    - Schmidt, Gerhardt, 1 letter
    - Schmitt, Francis O. Schmitt, Kenneth C. (1) Schneider, Howard A. (2), 3 letters
    - Scholastic Magazine, 1958-1963; 49 letters
      - Correspondence primarily with Eric Berger
      - Member Bd of Consultants
        Includes numerous.
      - mss reviews and 1963 Mar note on actinomycin, 1963 March
    - Schramm, G. Concerning 1969 Sept 14-17 Tubingen Miescher Symposium opening address, 2 letters
    - Schreiber, Morris, 5 letters
    - Schultz, Jack, 1952 May 15; 9 letters
      Includes items on 1952 May 15 Philadelphia address Schwarz Bio Research Lab (1).
    - Science, 1951-1974; 67 letters
      Includes numerous mss reviews.
    - Science Service. Christmas Lectures questionnaire, 1 letter
  - Sc (Box 13)
    Scientific American.
    - Scientific American, 1951-1973; 110 letters
      Correspondence primarily with Dennis Flanagan.
      Includes numerous mss reviews; planning material for 1961 Sept issue "The Living Cell"; article suggestions; some A.E. Mirsky mss working material; Max Perutz and M.H.F. Wilkins letters to The Editor concerning "The Double Helix", 1961 Sept.
  - Se (Box 13)
    - Seitz, Frederick, 1968-1974; 61 letters
      Includes draft memorandum on RU contributions to methods, instruments, tools of research and comments.
  - Sco-Seshac (Box 13)
    - Scott, Eugene. Job inquiry for L. Murthy, 2 letters
    - Segal, Sheldon J. 1 holograph, 3 letters
    - Sehgal, P.P., 1 letter
    - Sela, Ben-Ami, 1 letter
    - Selzer, Golda, 1954-1963; 4 letters
    - Seno, S., 1966 October 17-21; 18 letters
      Includes items on job inquiry for T. Kimoto; Japan symposium, planned to attend but cancelled (wife's illness) Servac Laboratories (1).
    - Serra, J.A., 4 letters
    - Seshachar, B.R., 1963-1971; 14 letters
      Includes Vasanthi (Bhandary) evaluation.
  - Seshai-Simo (Box 13)
    - Seshaiya, R.V., 20 letters
      Includes items on materials sent to Shacklee, James (3) Admission application with college transcript.
    - Sharma, A.K., 17 letters
    - Shaver, John, 1 letter
    - Sheath, Geoffrey, 2 letters
    - Sheath, Graham, 2 letters
    - Shell Oil Co., 1 letter
    - Shelton, Robert S., 3 letters
    - Sherman, Robert, 1 letter
    - Shimazono, Norio, 2 letters
    - Shockley, Wm., 1 letter
    - Shope, Richard E., 1 letter
    - Shore, Richard E., 1 letter
    - Shortman, Ken, 2 letters
    - Shugar, D., 2 letters
    - Sibatani, Atuhiro, 1949-1966; 29 letters
      Includes work evaluation.
    - Sigma Xi. became member, 1958 November 25; 15 letters
    - Silha, Milan, 2 letters
    - Silva, Jacqueline da, 2 letters
    - Siminovitch, David. Ottawa address, 1958 February; 7 letters
    - Simmons, Jack Jr., 3 letters
    - Simon, Harold. Student progress examination, 1 letter
  - Si (Box 13)
    - Silverman, Bert, 1968-1973; 63 letters
      Includes 1 holograph on Canada visit.
  - Simp-Ste (Box 13)
    - Simpson, Hoke S., 4 letters
    - Singh, B.W., 2 letters
    - Sippel, Theodore O. University of Michigan seminar, 1964 March 4; 2 letters
    - Sirlin, J.L., 1959-1970; 7 letters
      Includes recommendation for; Bruce McEwen recommendation.
    - Skeels, Harold M., 3 letters
    - Slater, Donald, 2 letters
    - Slater, Grant G., 1 letter
    - Slor, Hanoch, 2 letters
    - Smellie, R.M.S., 1 letter
    - Smilansky, Moshe, 3 letters
    - Smulson, Mark E. Ms review, 2 letters
    - Sobczak, E., 2 letters
    - Society for Experimental Biology and Medicine, 3 letters
    - Solomon, Arthur K., 7 letters
    - Solum, John H., 1 letter
    - Sonin, Robert, 1 letter
    - Sonneborn, David, 3 letters
    - Sonneborn, T.M., 5 letters
      Includes Hans Ris evaluation.
    - Sorem, Kevin, 2 letters
    - Sosa, Julio Maria, 1 letter
    - Soskice, Blazena. Holograph, 1 letter
    - Sotheran, Henry Ltd., 8 letters
    - Southwick, Charles H., 1 letter
    - Sparrow, Arnold H., 2 letters
    - Sparvoli, E., 2 letters
    - Spencer, E. Martin, 3 letters
    - Spencer, John H., 2 letters
    - Springer-Verlag, 2 letters
    - Spyrides, George, 9 letters
      Includes thesis examination evaluation.
    - Stanley, Julian C., 1 letter
    - Stanley, W., 1 letter
    - Stebbins, G. Ledyard, 13 letters
      Includes job inquiry for E. Yagil.
    - Stein, Gary S., 4 letters
    - Stein, Maxine, 2 letters
    - Stein, William H., 3 letters
      Includes Arthur Karlin thesis evaluation.
    - Steinert, W., 1 letter
    - Steinitz, H., 1 letter
    - Stenish, J.J., 2 letters
    - Stephanson, S.K., 1 letter
    - Stern, Curt, 1956-1969; 6 letters
      Includes review of Daedalus ms "The Continuity of Genetics" Stern, Herbert (19) Includes promotion recommendation to Dr. Gasser; Stern reprints Steubing, William C. (2).
    - Stevens, Audrey, 6 letters
    - Stewart, Caroll, 2 letters
    - Stewart, Florence M., 4 letters
    - Stewart, James, 1 letter
  - Sti-Sz (Box 14)
    - Stinnett, Nan, 2 letters
    - Stocken, Lloyd A., 8 letters
    - Stoll, N.R., 1 letter
    - Stollar, B. David, 5 letters
      Includes A. Sivak grant proposal evaluation.
    - Stollar, James, 2 letters
    - Stone, Frederick L., 3 letters
    - Stone, Wilson S. 1 holograph, 4 letters
    - Straub, Bruno, 1955 August; 4 letters
      Includes item on 1955 Aug Brussels Int' l Congress of Biochemistry.
    - Strehler, Bernard L., 10 letters
      Includes items on Kanungo ms Stricks, Walter (5).
    - Strittmatter, Cornelius F. Job inquiry for Carolyn Burdick, 2 letters
    - Stroun, Maurice, 6 letters
    - Stubblefield, Elton. Ms review for publication in PNAS, 4 letters
    - Sugo, H.C., 2 letters
    - Sunderlin, C.E., 2 letters
    - Sung, Michael, 2 letters
    - Sutton, Joseph, 5 letters
    - Suzuki, David, 11 letters
      Includes 1965 Apr 8 Vancouver seminar, planned to attend but cancelled (wife's illness).
    - Sweetman, Lawrence, 1 letter
    - Swift, Hewson, 9 letters
    - Symons, R.H., 2 letters
    - Szego, Clara M., 1 letter
    - Szilard, Leo. Dealing with Cuban invasion, 4 letters
  - T-Tros (Box 14)
    - Tagnon, H.J., 3 letters
      Includes J.G. Georgatsos et al ms review.
    - Takahashi, T., 1 letter
    - Talbot, Timothy R., 1 letter
    - Talmud, Bela, 1 letter
    - Talwar, C.P., 9 letters
    - Tamiya, Nobuo. Numerous items dealing with mass spectrometer donation, 22 letters
    - Tamm, Igor, 3 letters
    - Tanz, Rose and Ralph, 1 letter
    - Tatum, Edward, 4 letters
      Includes comments on Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory sponsorship program; 1 holograph.
    - Taylor, Howard C., 1 letter
    - Taylor, J. Herbert. Recommendation for Taylor, R.M. (2) L.H. Cohen grant proposal evaluation Television (4) Science and Engineering Television Journal, 3 letters
    - Teuber, Hans-Lukas, 1 letter
    - Thoday, J.M. 1 holograph concerning Durkheim, 3 letters
    - Thode, H.G., 2 letters
    - Thomas, Lewis, 1 letter
    - Thomson, D.L., 5 letters
      Includes M.A. Enesco thesis evaluation Timonen, K. Sakari (5).
    - Ting, K.P., 2 letters
    - Tobacco Industry Research Committee (l)
    - Tobach, Ethel, 2 letters
    - Tobey, R.A., 2 letters
    - Toennies, G. Ms review, 2 letters
    - Tomasz, Alexander, 1 letter
    - Tomkins, John, 2 letters
    - Trager, Wm. 1 holograph recommendation to Birge, 3 letters
    - Trebilcox, Hal C., 2 letters
    - Troshin, A.S., 7 letters
      Includes items on RI visit.
  - Trow-Ty (Box 14)
    - Trowell, Hugh, 2 letters
    - Truant, A.P., 1 letter
    - Truscott, Frederick, 2 letters
    - Ts'o, Paul O.P., 8 letters
      Includes chapter review.
    - Tuchman, Jessica. Student admission application, 2 letters
    - Tunick, J.A,., 2 letters
    - Turba, F., 2 letters
    - Turner, Bruce J., 14 letters
    - Twitty, Victor, 1952-1968; 24 letters
      Includes recommendation for Niu; Guggenheim fellowship recommendation to Moe for Twitty Tyler, Albert (8); 2 holographs.
  - U-Vi (Box 14)
    - Ubell, Earl. 1958 Mar 20 NY Herald Tribune Address; 1960 James T. Grady medal nominating letter for Ubell; 1961 Mar Princeton Science Information Conference participant; 1964 Aug WNEW radio program plans, 23 letters
    - Uland, Beth, 1 letter
    - Umschau in Wissenschaft und Technik, 1 letter
    - Unesco, 3 letters
      Includes comments on "Statement on Race".
    - University of Chicago Press
    - University of Madras, 3 letters
    - University of Michigan, 1964 March 18; 11 letters
      Includes 1964 March 18 address.
    - Unsworth, B.R., 2 letters
    - Vallentin, Kerstin, 14 letters
    - Venekamp, J. H., 3 letters
    - Venkataraman, P.R., 1 letter
    - Venkitasubramanian, T.A., 2 letters
    - Ventilla, Marta. Admission application, 2 letters
    - Ventron Instrument Corp., 1 letter
    - Vidalio, Georgio, 1 letter
    - Vincent, Russell A., 1 letter
    - Vinokouroff, C., 2 letters
    - Vishniac, Roman, 7 letters
  - Vo-Vr (Box 14)
    - Voeller, Bruce R., 9 letters
    - Volkin, Elliot, 6 letters
      Includes ms review.
    - von Muralt, Alexander. Concerning R. Meudt, 2 letters
    - Vorbrodt, Andrzej, 4 letters
      Includes comments on amino acid uptake paper.
    - Vorobyov, Vladimir (various spellings of Vorobyov), 1957-1965; 53 letters
    - Vovis, Gerald F. Vratsanos, Spyros M. (4), 2 letters
  - W-We (Box 14)
    - Wahrman, Jacob, 3 letters
    - Waksman, Selman, 1 letter
    - Wald, George, 4 letters
    - Walker, Peter, 4 letters
      Includes job inquiry for N. Maclean; comments on ms.
    - Wallace, Bruce, 3 letters
      Includes statement on resolution to NAS concerning secret projects.
    - Walton, Clarence, 2 letters
    - Wannier, Peter. Admission application with transcripts, 4 letters
    - Warmke, H.E., 2 letters
    - Washington, University of, 2 letters
    - Waters, L.L. Recommendation for Syożo Osawa, 2 letters
    - Watson, Adam, 2 letters
    - Watson, C.J., 6 letters
    - Watson, R.W., 1958 February 26; 17 letters
      Includes items on: Job inquiry for K.R. Hanson; 1958 Feb 26 Nat'1 Research Council, Ottawa, Canada address.
    - Weaver, Warren. 1 holograph; recommendations for Yamada and Reverberi; Rockefeller Foundation grant for 1954 African trip, 27 letters
    - Webster, C., 2 letters
    - Wedekind, Gerhard, 1 letter
    - Weiss, Paul, 1952 August-September; 18 letters
      Includes items on: 1952 Aug and Sept Utrecht and Stockholm conferences and travel grant to attend; referees remarks on mss for Paul Weiss.
    - Weisstein, Ulrich, 2 letters
    - Weizmann Institute of Science, 7 letters
    - Wepf & Co., 2 letters
    - Westra, Miss, 1 letter
  - Wh (Box 15)
    - Whaley, Cordon. University of Texas addresses; 1968 addresses cancelled, 1958 March 31-April 3; 18 letters
    - Wheelock, E. Frederick. Bibliography for Fluorescent-Antibody Technique, 3 letters
    - Whelan, W.J., 3 letters
    - Whitaker, Douglas, 17 letters
    - White, Abraham, 1 letter
    - White, Burton L. Ms on "The Development of Perception During the First Six Months of Life", 1 letter
    - White, E. Grace. Comments on chapter for "Genetics", 2 letters
    - White, F.E. Concerning J. Buchowicz and A. Przelecka (Polish scientists) visit to RU, 6 letters
    - White, Harold (Mrs.).Donation to RU Library Leslie Webster Labrador diary, 2 letters
    - White, Michael. Job inquiry for Barry Fabian, 1 letter
    - Whitelock, Otto v. St. NY Academy of Sciences paper, 1957 January 7-9; 2 letters
    - Whitemore, Clifford S., 2 letters
  - Wi-Wy (Box 15)
    - Wiche, Gerhard, 2 letters
    - Wigglesworth, V.B., 3 letters
      Includes examiner report of K. Madhavan thesis.
    - Wilbrandt, Walter, 3 letters
    - Wilhelm, Ottmar, 1 letter
    - Wilkes, A., 1 letter